Okay, so hello everyone in this video, we are going to work with the other components, okay?
So as you can see that I have pasted some of the code for the styling part, okay?
So this message input, let's do one thing, copy all of this and I will create one text file
in the stylesbiner.
So text file with the name message input, message input to dot txt and control v, save this
one and after this, for the messages part also I have created this one.
So you can analyze that if you want, so I will just control c and create one more file here
and that is message is dot txt, go there, just paste it, okay?
So I have pasted all of this and now we have to work on the rendering logic, okay?
So so where should we start?
So we should start with the chat container part, we can add some styling in it, okay?
So let's add some style inside of this class name equal to let's add flex and flex
call and height should be full and PG base 100 shadow, large and for the mid-screens, the width
will be auto, okay, control and save.
So if we just go to the front and side, we can see the changes, okay, there's some rendering
issue log in, okay, on MD major is not defined, okay?
No, I choose, go here, we will check up on these, okay?
So all of these errors, where it is coming, okay, okay?
So I think it should be here in this MD major, so we can, what we can actually do is import
the two images that I have just used here, okay?
So from react icon, so import, let's do it quickly, MD image, MD image, from react dash icons,
icon slash MD, and after this we are going to just import L use send horizontal, what
horizontal, from react dash icons, slash L U. Now let's check on these, refresh days,
it's quite slow in loading, so as we can see that here this input box is here and also
this image, and along with this, there's some send button there, this cross icon, as you
can see, and for the messages part, I've pasted this, so no need to worry about that,
so you can find it here, message is dot the JSX, so actually the incoming message I have
commented here, so you have class name, and hello, how are you?
And after this, this is the outgoing message part, okay, so I am good, thanks, but that's
what is getting displayed here, as you can see.
So now after this, okay, we are actually missing some of the styling I guess, so what we should
do is go to this chat container, and we have placed it one over the chat header messages
and all, so what we can actually do is, we have already added a styles here div class
name, so let's wrap everything inside a div, so div class name equals to suppose it would
be flex, flex one, overflow, y, auto, okay, I think it should, the messages part should
be inside of this one, so we will see the changes here, okay, so that would be fine, I
guess, yeah, that's looking good only, now for the messages input, we can also give that,
so let's make another div, and we can see that this is slightly towards the left side,
we can change this to center, okay, so flex shrink one padding should be four, and background
base 200, and take this and wrap this message input, so let's see what changes there,
log in this one, I think this is a good part, like this is flex shrink one, we can add
some margin to the left, like five, little more, it should be fine, I guess, okay, now it's
looking good, now this thing is over, now actually what we can do is let's go to the home page
and check the styling thing, chat container, okay, so here we have already added all the
styles, right side bar is also included, div class name equal to this, that's fine, I guess, this should be fine.
And now, okay, so now let's work with another component, like suppose if there's no chat is selected,
in that case, we can make another JSX file, so no chat selected dot JSX dot JSX, okay, so const no chat
selected equals to this component and return one div H1, here welcome, welcome to chat app, right,
after this we can add one paragraph, like this is your, what we can add home page, where you can
where you can start chatting with your friends, chatting with your friends, okay and then export
default export default this section, no chat selected, then now after this we can also add styling
for this one, so I guess div and then H1 now it's fine only, so let's modify the changes
inside of our chat store dot JS, since we have the users now in our UI, for this part we can
say that selected users, like if there are some selected users, we can set the value as null,
okay, give comma, and after this in the home page, as we can see this styling is
okay, right, there's no need to change the stylings, I guess, this is sidebar, this is chat
container, I guess this one should be okay, and yeah, one thing, we need to import the chat store
here, okay, and we need to just do one thing, like get the selected users,
since we want to render all of that thing inside of our home page only, okay, so from the chat
store we are getting the selected users, and for the selected users, we out to render it, right,
so let's add some conditional statement here, like if selected user exist, then in that case,
we are going to display the chat container, chat container component,
otherwise we can say that whatever, like, yeah, no chat selected, okay,
so this component we have already made, and so for that we are just from this hook,
from the chat store, we are getting this selected user, and just rendering using this logic,
like if the selected user is true, then in that case, we are just displaying the chat container,
otherwise we are displaying that there's no chat selected, that's it, and what actually,
now we can do is for the no chat selected, right, so we can go to this no chat selected,
it's quite basic UI, so for this one, first wrap this inside of one open brace, open brackets,
okay, and, okay, so we can import some few icons, like,
a file message, square, I guess, square or circle, whatever, after this,
we can display it to the top, like a file message, square, class name, we can add some tailwind
styles here as well, so it would be text, text, 5 Excel, and after 5 Excel we can add text,
I guess purple would be fine, purple, 600, and animation, some animation, bounce,
then BG, gray, background, gray, 800, all right, padding should be two, and rounded, large,
okay, so we can do that, let's see, how it's getting displayed, okay, so for this one,
welcome to chat app, this is your homepage where you can start chatting with your friends, okay,
but this is quite weird, I think there's some messing with the styling, so we can remove this,
and we need to add some more styling here, okay, and we need to fix this styling part,
this fit is getting quite longer, I will fix this one, and we'll meet you in the next video,